# Zynthia Martinez

Philadelphia, PA | 610-905-6283 | www.zynthiamartinez.com | zynthia.martinez@gmail.com

# **Summary**

Dedicated Instructional Designer possessing over 10 years of experience in authoring on-line courses and ancillary resources to support various learning styles, developing standards to streamline training programs, and partnering with all levels of management. Possess exceptional skills with User Experience, Graphic Design, Project Management, Quality Assurance and Testing, and Learning Management Systems.

#### **Technical Skills**

Articulate Storyline, Cornerstone On-Demand LMS, Adobe Acrobat, Adobe Photoshop, MS Office Suite, Google Suite, Trello, Confluence and Jira.

# **Experience**

#### INSTRUCTIONAL DESIGNER | CREATIVE WHISK | 2014 - PRESENT

As an Instructional Designer, evaluate business objectives and optimize training procedures. This includes implementing solutions that reduce the learning curve of new innovative programs.

- Communicate technical details from Software Developers and functionality requirements from Subject Matter Experts to improve customer experience with the deployment of new applications.
- · Monitor team progress and determine project prioritization.
- · Assemble training resources such as user guides, technical manuals, and infographics to assist onboarding of the sales force and customers with the latest web-based software platform.
- · Develop engaging online training modules using Articulate Storyline.
- · Assist with technical support on the learning management systems platform.
- Establish metrics to evaluate program success, budget, and efficiency.

#### E-LEARNING DEVELOPER | LMS CONSULTING | 2011 - 2014

Customers included high profile businesses as TENA, Tork and, Villanova University.

- Developed and maintained 75+ E-Learning modules and training materials for new hires.
- · Supported the Training Department with technical issues involving software use.
- · Assisted in the transition to a new LMS platform by QA and validating setting compatibility.

#### MULTIMEDIA PROJECT COORDINATOR | SYNTHES | 2004 - 2011

Main duties included developing computer-based trainings and upkeeping of digital assets.

- · Coordinated with Project Managers and surgeons to develop training courses for medical residents.
- · Collaborated with subject matter experts to convert classroom training to online courses.
- · Organized video crews, editors, and vendors to produce product use videos, surgeries and interviews.

# **Other Experience**

## OWNER/OPERATOR | ZYNNIE BAKES | 2013 - 2014

Pursued a passion to open a retail shop. Brought together the local community and supported other small businesses. Managed daily operations as well as performed the following tasks:

- Interviewed and oversaw vendors to ensure that the contracted work followed specifications and guidelines.
- · Supported fundraisers, charity, and local businesses such as Philabundance, Food Trust, Hope Chest, Free the Girls, Replica Creative, Downingtown Main Street Association.
- Appealed to the neighborhood association and the Zoning Board of Adjustments regarding converting a mixed-use residential property to include a commercial space.

### Education

#### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | WEST CHESTER UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA

· Major: Business Management

#### Volunteer

- Proud to provide volunteer services to the Veteran's Multi-Service Center and Street Trails Animal Rescue (STAR.)
- · Organizer of Philadelphia Instructional Designer Meetup group